Guide to the Palo Alto-Stanford Hospital Collection
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Palo Alto-Stanford Hospital collection
1938-1966
1953-1966
SC0086
Stanford University
1.5 Linear feet
Collection consists of two parts. The first pertains to Stanford's acquisition of Palo Alto's share of the hospital and includes correspondence, legal documents, financial reports, and floor plans, 1951-1966. The second part consists of scrapbooks and clippings, 1938-1960, on the Palo Alto-Stanford hospital, health insurance programs, labor unions in hospitals, Stanford Medical School, and other hospitals.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
In 1921 Stanford University took over the administration of Palo Alto's Peninsula Hospital; ownership was jointly shared by Palo Alto and Stanford. In 1931 a new hospital building was opened on university land. In July 1968 Stanford University became the sole owner of the Palo Alto-Stanford Hospital.
Description of the Collection
Collection consists of two parts. The first pertains to Stanford's acquisition of Palo Alto's share of the hospital and includes correspondence, legal documents, financial reports, and floor plans, 1951-1966. The second part consists of scrapbooks and clippings, 1938-1960, on the Palo Alto-Stanford hospital, health insurance programs, labor unions in hospitals, Stanford Medical School, and other hospitals.
Access Terms
Palo Alto-Stanford Hospital Center.; Stanford University. Hospital.; Stanford University. School of Medicine.; Hospitals, University.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Correspondence re acquisition of the Palo Alto half of the hospital, 1964 May - 1966 March (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence re acquisition of the Palo Alto half of the hospital, 1966 April - 1966 November (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Palo Alto-Stanford hospital center basic legal documents (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Appraisal of Palo Alto half of hospital; tables and charts re relative Palo Alto/Stanford ownership; report of joint owner committee, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous notes re purchase of the hospital (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Financial reports (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Annual budgets, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Auditors reports, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Annual budgets, 1951-1953, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Supporting documents for the 1952-1953 budget (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Palo Alto-Stanford hospital floor plans (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Legal agreements, contracts, and leases between Stanford and Palo Alto re hospital (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Palo Alto-Stanford Hospital Medical Center developments and dedication, clippings, 1959 April 30 - November 19 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Palo Alto Hospital, news and transfer to Stanford Medical Center, clippings, 1959 February 21 - December 3 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Palo Alto-Stanford Medical Center, medical developments, clippings, 1959 February 27 - October 14 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Stanford-Lane Hospital, San Francisco, clippings, 1959 February 3 - October 15 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Health insurance programs clippings, 1959 February 16 - August 3 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Palo Alto hospital scrapbook, 1938 January 26 - 1953 September 26 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Palo Alto hospital scrapbook, 1954 July 5 - December 13 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Palo Alto hospital scrapbook, 1958 January 3 - 1959 January 27 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Stanford medical school, medical developments, clippings, 1956 July 8 - 1958 December 24 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Palo Alto-Stanford Hospital, financial difficulties, clippings, 1960 March 24-26 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bay area hospitals, miscellaneous clippings, 1956 May 19 - 1958 October 7 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bay area hospitals, miscellaneous clippings, 1958 October 19 - 1959 February 9 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Labor unions in hospitals, clippings, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Palo Alto-Stanford expansion project, clippings, 1953 July 28 - 1956 July 11 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Palo Alto-Stanford expansion project, clippings, 1956 July 18 - 1959 October 2 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Stanford medical school, clippings, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Other hospital, clippings, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 7)